<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>Memoirs</title>
		<link>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme</link>
		<description>I will take you on the fabulous world of exploration. Travel, culture, lifestyle. Eat, Pray, Love!</description>
		<copyright>Memoirs</copyright>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 07:48:02 GMT</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 07:48:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<item>
			<title>Les Ambassadeurs, the first Restaurant we Visited in Paris</title>
			<link>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/02/les-ambassadeurs.html</link>
			<description>The first restaurant we visited in Paris</description>
			<enclosure url="https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/img/e73b93a01332ac556c73823f9550a5f4-2.jpg" length="0" type="image" />
			<guid>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/02/les-ambassadeurs.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>
    &lt;p&gt;Within the Hôtel de Crillon, which was built in 1758, Les Ambassadeurs operated as a restaurant since the mid-19th century. It reached its peak of fame as a restaurant and nightclub (a café-concert) in the last three decades of the 19th century.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always a center of entertainment for the aristocracy, in the 1870s it also became a regular destination of some of the best known figures of art and the demi-monde. Edgar Degas and Henri de Toulouse-Lautrec portrayed visitors at the night club, and Aristide Bruant performed there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It was decorated in an 18th-century rococo style, redesigned by Sybille de Margérie with furnishings by Sonia Rykiel.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following a renovation of the hotel in 1981–85, the restaurant occupied a former private ballroom with windows looking out on the Place de la Concorde, a few hundred meters from the Palais Garnier.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les Ambassadeurs had two Michelin stars. In the last decade of its operation, chef was Dominique Bouchet &amp;nbsp;followed by Jean-François Piège and finally when the hotel closed in 2013 for an extended renovation, Christopher Hache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017 Hache opened a smaller restaurant, L'Écrin, within the renovated hotel; the former space of Les Ambassadeurs became a bar.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
			<comments xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</comments>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Much more than a desert: A trip into the Sahara</title>
			<link>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/02/much-more-than-a-desert-a-trip-to-sahara.html</link>
			<description>It's not just sand and heat; there's a world of hidden treasures, yours to discover</description>
			<enclosure url="https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/img/e73b93a01332ac556c73823f9550a5f4-16.jpg" length="0" type="image" />
			<guid>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/02/much-more-than-a-desert-a-trip-to-sahara.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>
    &lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sahara is a desert located on the African continent. It is the largest hot desert in the world, and the third largest desert overall after Antarctica and the Arctic. Its area of 9,200,000 square kilometres (3,600,000 sq mi) is comparable to the area of China or the United States.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The name 'Sahara' is derived from a dialectal Arabic word for "desert", ṣaḥra (صحرا /ˈsˤaħra/).”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Landscape&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The desert comprises much of North Africa, excluding the fertile region on the Mediterranean Sea coast, the Atlas Mountains of the Maghreb, and the Nile Valley in Egypt and Sudan. It stretches from the Red Sea in the east and the Mediterranean in the north to the Atlantic Ocean in the west, where the landscape gradually changes from desert to coastal plains.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Regions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the south, it is bounded by the Sahel, a belt of &lt;em&gt;semi-arid tropical savanna&lt;/em&gt; around the Niger River valley and the Sudan Region of Sub-Saharan Africa. The Sahara can be divided into several regions including: the western Sahara, the central Ahaggar Mountains, the Tibesti Mountains, the Aïr Mountains, the Ténéré desert, and the Libyan Desert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For several hundred thousand years, the Sahara has alternated between desert and savanna grassland in a 20,000 year cycle caused by the precession of the Earth's axis as it rotates around the Sun, which changes the location of the North African Monsoon. The area is next expected to become green in about 15,000 years (17,000 AD).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
			<comments xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</comments>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>One day we just started our adventure</title>
			<link>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/01/one-day-just-started-adventure.html</link>
			<description>Don't wait, go for it!</description>
			<enclosure url="https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/img/e73b93a01332ac556c73823f9550a5f4-15.jpg" length="0" type="image" />
			<guid>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/01/one-day-just-started-adventure.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>
    &lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&amp;nbsp;”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll... originated with us”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
			<comments xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</comments>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>London is that kind of place you must visit in this lifetime</title>
			<link>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/01/london.html</link>
			<description>London is that kind of place you must visit in this lifetime</description>
			<enclosure url="https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/img/e73b93a01332ac556c73823f9550a5f4-9.jpg" length="0" type="image" />
			<guid>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/01/london.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>
    &lt;p&gt;The Queen's Guard and Queen's Life Guard (called King's Guard and King's Life Guard when the reigning monarch is male) are the names given to contingents of infantry and cavalry soldiers charged with guarding the official royal residences in the United Kingdom. The British Army has regiments of both Horse Guards and Foot Guards predating the English Restoration (1660), and since the reign of King Charles II these regiments have been responsible for guarding the Sovereign's palaces. The Guards are fully operational soldiers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Queen's Guard and Queen's Life Guard are mounted at the royal residences that come under the operating area of the British Army's London District, which is responsible for the administration of the Household Division. This covers Buckingham Palace, St James's Palace and the Tower of London, as well as Windsor Castle. The Queen's Guard is also mounted at the sovereign's other official residence, the Palace of Holyroodhouse, but not as often as in London. In Edinburgh, the guard is the responsibility of the resident infantry battalion at Redford Barracks. It is not mounted at the Queen's private residences at Sandringham or Balmoral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Queen's Guard is the name given to the contingent of infantry responsible for guarding Buckingham Palace and St James's Palace (including Clarence House) in London. The guard is made up of a company of soldiers from a single regiment, which is split in two, providing a detachment for Buckingham Palace and a detachment for St James's Palace. Because the Sovereign's official residence is still St James's, the guard commander (called the captain of the guard) is based there, as are the regiment's colours.&amp;nbsp;”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Sovereign is in residence, the Queen's Guard numbers three officers and forty other ranks, with four sentries each posted at Buckingham Palace (on the forecourt) and St James's Palace (two in Friary Court, two at the entrance to Clarence House).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reduces to three officers and 31 ORs, with two sentries each, when the Sovereign is not in residence. The Queen's Guard is not purely ceremonial in nature. They provide sentries during the day and night, and during the later hours, they patrol the grounds of the Palace.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until 1959, the sentries at Buckingham Palace were stationed outside the fence. This stopped following an incident involving a female tourist and a Coldstream Guardsman – due to the continued pestering by tourists and sightseers, the guardsman kicked the tourist on the ankle as he marched. The tourist made a complaint to the police and the sentry was confined to barracks for ten days. Not long after, the sentries were moved inside the fence.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
			<comments xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</comments>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Kontent.Statiq makes image management easy</title>
			<link>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/01/easy-images.html</link>
			<description>Kontent and Statiq handle images for your static website</description>
			<enclosure url="https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/img/e73b93a01332ac556c73823f9550a5f4-photo-1559925393-8be0ec4767c8.jfif" length="0" type="image" />
			<guid>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/01/easy-images.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>
    &lt;p&gt;Managing images can be a challenging task, I know that, but Statiq.Kontent makes it so much simpler. Just upload it to the media library and insert in your page with the appropriate size. Kontent will take care of resizing it and Kontent.Statiq will download it into your static site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Education must also train one for quick, resolute and effective thinking. To think incisively and to think for one's self is very difficult.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“&amp;nbsp;We are prone to let our mental life become invaded by legions of half truths, prejudices, and propaganda. At this point, I often wonder whether or not education is fulfilling its purpose. A great majority of the so-called educated people do not think logically and scientifically.&amp;nbsp;”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the press, the classroom, the platform, and the pulpit in many instances do not give us objective and unbiased truths. To save man from the morass of propaganda, in my opinion, is one of the chief aims of education. Education must enable one to sift and weigh evidence, to discern the true from the false, the real from the unreal, and the facts from the fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function of education, therefore, is to teach one to think intensively and to think critically. But education which stops with efficiency may prove the greatest menace to society. The most dangerous criminal may be the man gifted with reason, but with no morals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The late Eugene Talmadge, in my opinion, possessed one of the better minds of Georgia, or even America. Moreover, he wore the Phi Beta Kappa key. By all measuring rods, Mr. Talmadge could think critically and intensively; yet he contends that I am an inferior being. Are those the types of men we call educated?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must remember that intelligence is not enough. Intelligence plus character--that is the goal of true education. The complete education gives one not only power of concentration, but worthy objectives upon which to concentrate. The broad education will, therefore, transmit to one not only the accumulated knowledge of the race but also the accumulated experience of social living.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
			<comments xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</comments>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Spoilers Inside - a film review needs hidden spoilers like this post</title>
			<link>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/01/spoilers-inside.html</link>
			<description>Here's how you can hide part of your article to prevent spoiling other peoples fun.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/img/e73b93a01332ac556c73823f9550a5f4-12.jpg" length="0" type="image" />
			<guid>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/01/spoilers-inside.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>
    &lt;p&gt;Director Roland Suso Richter's enigmatic psychological thriller (direct to video/DVD) was based upon screenwriter Michael Cooney's own play "Point of Death" - a title that gave away the film's entire plot twist premise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in many similar films, such as Jacob's Ladder (1990), Soul Survivors (2001), and The Butterfly Effect (2004), events and people were thoroughly distorted and confused because the protagonist was at the point of death. The tagline was misleading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"When You Don't Have a Memory, How Can You Remember Who to Trust?"&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="spoiler"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mind-warping film opened with a hospital patient Simon Cable (Ryan Phillippe) awakening in a hospital with little knowledge (amnesia perhaps?) of what had happened, and why he was there, etc. He was told by attending Dr. Jeremy Newman (Stephen Rea) that it was July 29, 2002 (Simon thought it was the year 2000 - he was confused - he heard a doctor say 20:00 hours!) and that he had died for two minutes from cardiac arrest following the near-fatal accident -- but he had been revived ("You're as good as new").Dr. Newman: "Simon, this is the 29th of July. The year is 2002. And your wife, whose name is Anna, is waiting outside."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What do the critics say?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“There's almost no single moment in Portrait of a Lady on Fire that couldn't be captured, mounted, and hung on a wall as high art.” ⸺ &lt;cite&gt;Entertainment Weekly&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major clue to everything that truly happened was the scene that played next under the credits - hospital staff failed to bring a patient back to life with a defibrillator after a car accident. Chest compressions failed and there was no pulse. A second major clue was provided by hospital orderly Travis (Stephen Graham): Everybody dies. No mystery there. But why and how everyone dies. Now, there's a mystery worth solving. Probably the biggest mystery there is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;So how do we add spoilers in this theme?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drop a spoiler in the body of your post :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure data-asset-id="b921df44-f649-41e4-8345-7817df9f041d" data-image-id="b921df44-f649-41e4-8345-7817df9f041d"&gt;&lt;img src="https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/memoirs-theme/img/kontent-insert-spoiler.png" data-asset-id="b921df44-f649-41e4-8345-7817df9f041d" data-image-id="b921df44-f649-41e4-8345-7817df9f041d" alt=""&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it will render like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-html"&gt;&amp;lt;div class="spoiler"&amp;gt;My blurred paragraph here.&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content:encoded>
			<comments xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</comments>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>That day when we almost missed our flight</title>
			<link>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/01/that-day-when-we-almost-missed-our-flight.html</link>
			<description>On the origins of odd-shaped books</description>
			<enclosure url="https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/img/e73b93a01332ac556c73823f9550a5f4-17.jpg" length="0" type="image" />
			<guid>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/01/that-day-when-we-almost-missed-our-flight.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>
    &lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll... originated with us”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&amp;nbsp;”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
			<comments xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</comments>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Reviewing the best Oscar movies of all time</title>
			<link>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/01/review-oscar.html</link>
			<description>My review of Inception movie. Acting, plot and something else in this short description.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/img/e73b93a01332ac556c73823f9550a5f4-11.jpg" length="0" type="image" />
			<guid>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2020/01/review-oscar.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>
    &lt;p&gt;Review products, books, movies, restaurant and anything you like on your Kontent blog with **Memoirs**! JSON-LD ready for review property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to use?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's actually really simple! Add the rating in page in Kontent. It also supports halfs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure data-asset-id="6a88c3ce-1881-4b95-bdc9-dcdd7e7a8406" data-image-id="6a88c3ce-1881-4b95-bdc9-dcdd7e7a8406"&gt;&lt;img src="https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/memoirs-theme/img/rating.png" data-asset-id="6a88c3ce-1881-4b95-bdc9-dcdd7e7a8406" data-image-id="6a88c3ce-1881-4b95-bdc9-dcdd7e7a8406" alt="Specify the rating in Kontent"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</content:encoded>
			<comments xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</comments>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Observer - National Gallery of Art, Washington, United States</title>
			<link>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2019/12/the-observer-national-gallery-of-art.html</link>
			<description>The National Gallery of Art in Washington D.C. hosts a collection of paintings, drawings, prints, photographs, sculpture, medals, and decorative arts tracing the development of Western Art from the Middle Ages to the present.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/img/e73b93a01332ac556c73823f9550a5f4-1.jpg" length="0" type="image" />
			<guid>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2019/12/the-observer-national-gallery-of-art.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>
    &lt;p&gt;The National Gallery of Art, and its attached Sculpture Garden, is a national art museum in Washington, D.C., located on the National Mall, between 3rd and 9th Streets, at Constitution Avenue NW. Open to the public and free of charge, the museum was privately established in 1937 for the American people by a joint resolution of the United States Congress. Andrew W. Mellon donated a substantial art collection and funds for construction.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The core collection includes major works of art donated by Paul Mellon, Ailsa Mellon Bruce, Lessing J. Rosenwald, Samuel Henry Kress, Rush Harrison Kress, Peter Arrell Browne Widener, Joseph E. Widener, and Chester Dale.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gallery's collection of paintings, drawings, prints, photographs, sculpture, medals, and decorative arts traces the development of Western Art from the Middle Ages to the present, including the only painting by Leonardo da Vinci in the Americas and the largest mobile created by Alexander Calder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gallery's campus includes the original neoclassical West Building designed by John Russell Pope, which is linked underground to the modern East Building, designed by I. M. Pei, and the 6.1-acre (25,000 m2) Sculpture Garden.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gallery often presents temporary special exhibitions spanning the world and the history of art. It is one of the largest museums in North America.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
			<comments xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</comments>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Culinary Arts in Europe by Jean Anthelme Brillat-Savarin</title>
			<link>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2019/12/press-and-education.html</link>
			<description>On the evolution of cooking from the primitive discovery of fire to elite institutions governing the culinary arts.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/img/e73b93a01332ac556c73823f9550a5f4-7.jpg" length="0" type="image" />
			<guid>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2019/12/press-and-education.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>
    &lt;p&gt;The origins of culinary began with primitive humans roughly 2 million years ago. There are various theories as to how early humans used fire to cook meat. According to anthropologist Richard Wrangham, author of Catching Fire: How Cooking Made Us Human, primitive humans simply tossed a raw hunk of meat into the flames and watched it sizzle. Another theory claims humans may first have savoured roasted meat by chance when the flesh of a beast killed in a forest fire was found to be more appetizing and easier to chew and digest than the conventional raw meat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Culinary techniques improved with the introduction of earthenware and stoneware, the domestication of livestock, and advancements in agriculture. In early civilizations, the primary employers of professional chefs were kings, aristocrats, or priests. The divide between professional chefs cooking for the wealthy and peasants cooking for their families engendered the development of many cuisines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great deal of the study of Culinary Arts in Europe was organized by Jean Anthelme Brillat-Savarin, a man famous for his quote "Tell me what you eat, and I will tell you what you are," which has since been mistranslated and oversimplified into "You are what you eat." Other people helped to parse out the different parts of food science and gastronomy. Over time, increasingly deeper and more detailed studies into foods and the Culinary Arts has led to a greater wealth of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Asia, a similar path led to a separate study of the Culinary Arts, which later essentially merged with the Western counterpart. In the modern international marketplace, there is no longer a distinct divide between Western and Eastern foods. Culinary Arts students today, generally speaking, are introduced to the different cuisines of many different cultures from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Culinary Arts, in the Western world, as a craft and later as a field of study, began to evolve at the end of the Renaissance period. Prior to this, chefs worked in castles, cooking for kings and queens, as well as their families, guests, and other workers of the castle. As Monarchical rule became phased out as a modality, the chefs took their craft to inns and hotels. From here, the craft evolved into a field of study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before cooking institutions, professional cooks were mentors for individual students who apprenticed under them. In 1879, the first cooking school was founded in the United States: the Boston Cooking School. This school standardized cooking practices and recipes, and laid the groundwork for the culinary arts schools that would follow.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
			<comments xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</comments>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Education must also train one for quick, resolute and effective thinking.</title>
			<link>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2018/06/2018-06-12-education.html</link>
			<description>Prism highlighter is a very powerful thing. In this article I'm going to show you what you can actually do with it, some tricks and tips while editing your post. Tocs is also enabled as you can see in summary.</description>
			<enclosure url="https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/img/e73b93a01332ac556c73823f9550a5f4-3.jpg" length="0" type="image" />
			<guid>https://alanta.github.io/memoirs-theme/post/2018/06/2018-06-12-education.html</guid>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<content:encoded>
    &lt;p&gt;Memoirs theme has Prism highlighter integrated. I will show you in this post a few examples of how it looks if you are a developer planning to add pieces of code on your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;HTML&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-html"&gt;&amp;lt;li class="ml-1 mr-1"&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;a target="_blank" href="#"&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;i class="fab fa-twitter"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;CSS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-css"&gt;.highlight .c {
    color: #999988;
    font-style: italic; 
}
.highlight .err {
    color: #a61717;
    background-color: #e3d2d2; 
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Javascript&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-javascript"&gt;// alertbar later
$(document).scroll(function () {
    var y = $(this).scrollTop();
    if (y &amp;gt; 280) {
        $('.alertbar').fadeIn();
    } else {
        $('.alertbar').fadeOut();
    }
});&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-python"&gt;print("Hello World")&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ruby&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-ruby"&gt;require 'redcarpet'
markdown = Redcarpet.new("Hello World!")
puts markdown.to_html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;C#&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;Console.WriteLine($"Hello {DateTime.Now.Year}!");&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content:encoded>
			<comments xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>